Data Engineer and Backend Developer

# SRINIDHI SRIDHARAN

Phone: +91 98401 98626 Email: <a href="mailto:srinidhi.s96@gmail.com">srinidhi.s96@gmail.com</a>

Portfolio:





## **Professional Summary**

An Analytics consultant with 2 years of experience and well versed in data engineering and backend development especially in Cloud platforms. Has a proven track in working in Research based roles and later moving on to become data architect.

### **Technical Skills**

Database Development - SQL, NoSQL
Python for Data Science - Pyspark, Pandas
Java, Nodejs, C++
Data Modelling, Data Wrangling, Web Scraping
Hadoop, Apache Spark

SAP Cloud Platform - CloudFoundry Development
SAP HANA , SAP Predictive Analytics and BI Tools
ML Algorithms (Classification, Clustering, Regression)
R basics
Jenkins for CI

## **Education**

Bachelor of engineering, computer science and engineering – Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College

- CGPA: 8.84. University Rank Holder (Rank 24 out of 16,499 candidates under Anna University, Rank 3 in Overall CS department in College)
- Awarded endowment prize for best academic performance, recognition for consistent performance in Semesters by Department of Mathematics.
- Member of NSS, College Choir, Overall coordinator for technical events in University culturals.

HIGHER SECONDARY - D.A.V HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL, MAJOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Secured 97% and awarded a cash prize for best academic performance

CLASS X - HINDU SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL

- 10 CGPA. Present in Roll of Honour
- Multiple awards as vocalist in inter school culturals

## **Work Experience and Projects Handled**

### FREELANCER

ML PLATFORM DEVELOPMENT, ML ENGINEER - PAVO AND TUSKER INNOVATIONS (APRIL 2019 - MAY 2019)

### RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ML Engineer. Built and deployed a Spark engine using Pyspark and Pandas.
- Automated the process of data preparation, visualization based on cross validation techniques after fitting into model
- Interactive tool for Data Scientists to load data, choose models and visualize the prediction results.
- Algorithms Supported in Engine during Beta stage SVM Classifier, Logistic regression, Linear Regression, K-means clustering.

## ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT, DATA ENGINEERING - KAAR TECHNOLOGIES (Aug 2018 - JULY 2019)

PORTAL APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT - BACKEND DEVELOPER ,SAP CLOUD PLATFORM

CLIENT: SAP LABS - WALLDORF, GERMANY

#### RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Lead the Project on Sprint Deliverables and Architecture Analysis, creating User Story boards to track the Application Usage and User metrics.
- Responsible for Backend Database and API development using SAP HANA Database, Nodejs, Python and SAP ANALYTICS Cloud
- Early Adopter and Evangelist of SAP's New Cloud Foundry based Cloud Platform

ANALYTICS CONSULTANT, CENTER OF EXCELLENCE - KAAR TECHNOLOGIES (OCT 2017 - JULY 2018)

#### PROJECT IMPLEMENTATIONS:

REVAMPING THE REPORTING LANDSCAPE TO IN MEMORY COLUMNAR DATABASE WITH REAL TIME DATA INSIGHTS - BI CONSULTANT

DURATION: JAN 2018 - FEB 2018, MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

CLIENTS: DAVID BROWN SANTASALO, UNITED KINGDOM

FIRST SOLAR INC, UNITED STATES

#### RESPONSIBILITIES:

- **Guided** the customer on migrating the current Landscape to SAP In-Memory Data platform after analyzing the existing Reporting Landscape
- Revamped the Visualization Platform from Traditional BI to Modern SAP Fiori based UX and third party reporting tools
- Data Validation and Cleanup of Current Data Dictionary
- Visualization using Dashboards with Drill Down capabilities
- Worked with multiple BI tools SAP Analytics Cloud, SAP Embedded analytics , Tableau, MS Power BI

### PROOF OF CONCEPTS / PROJECT PROPOSAL:

- Architected the solution and Identified the Predictive Models for Industrial Incident Predictions (Apr 2018)
  - Architected the Platform for Running Predictive models on SAP HANA (In memory Database)
  - Historical Incident Analysis
  - Identified the suitable models for Incident Severity Classification and Accident Prediction based on Parameters like
     Employee Training
- Deployed ML Algorithms for Extended Warranty Rate Planning, Proof of Concept, SAP Predictive Analytics (Mar 2018)
  - Pioneered the usage of SAP Predictive Analytics Library feature
  - Utilized the Pareto Analysis or ABC Model to identify the top contributors to warranty Rate Planning
- Competitive Analysis of Partners Web Scraping and Segmentation for Marketing Team in Kaar Technologies (Dec 2017)
  - $\circ \quad \text{Set up Web crawler to Crawl through the Partner Websites and scrapped their information} \\$
  - O Data Modelling to obtain Relevant insights on their major selling products contributing to their revenue to understand Kaar's competitive edge.
- HEALTHCARE KPI DASHBOARDS FOR MINISTRY OF HEALTH, KINGDOM OF SAUDI ARABIA (Nov 2017)
  - Created dashboard Prototypes for a \$10M+ Analytics proposal demo
  - O **Identified** Key Performance Indicators for Healthcare and Diseases
  - o **Provided Solution** on Data Orchestration from multiple External Sources

### **Internships**

SMART DATA INTEGRATION - CENTER OF EXCELLENCE, KAAR TECHNOLOGIES

- Proof of concept\* on Smart Data Integration Remote access of data from cloud and on premise systems and visualizing it on SAP In memory columnar Database - HANA
- Initiated the integration of Virtual Data from External Cloud Sources.
- HANA and XSA administrator Revamped SAP HANA Platform to Support XSA Development and deploying predictive models
- Monitored and handled the Application and platform lifecycle management.
  - \*Proof of Concepts are created as part of feasibility analysis of an idea or an approach from technology standpoint.

PARALLEL PROCESSING USING HADOOP AND MAPREDUCE - BIG DATA DEVELOPER, KRISH IT

- Social Network Graph analysis using Hadoop MapReduce
- Working with unstructured Big data using Hadoop , Map Reduce in Python
- Initialized hadoop cluster nodes.

## **Volunteer Experience**

EX-COMMITTEE MEMBER AND COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR - SYMA, TRIPLICANE, CHENNAI

- Introduced the Computer Science Subject in their Growth Initiative and served as CS tutor for an year
- Hosted events , Digitized their charity activities

NATIONAL SERVICE SCHEME MEMBER, MEENAKSHI SUNDARARAJAN ENGINEERING COLLEGE

Spearheaded the Swachh bharat initiative inside my college

PYLADIES - MEETUP FOR WOMEN IN TECH

### **Awards and Achievement**

PANEL'S CHOICE - ONE DAY ANGEL HACKATHON, ANGEL HACK

Responsiblee - A Hyper-local application that provides credit scores to citizens based on their community participation. Played my part as Backend NOSQL developer using NoSQL Database - MongoDB.

ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE, MEENAKSHI SUNDARARAJAN COLLEGE

Awarded Silver medal as Endowment Prize for Academic Excellence in 4th and 5th semesters

BEST SINGER - ANNA UNIVERSITY , GUINDY

Emerged as the best singer in the intercollegiate music competition for NSS volunteers

MEMBER OF THE BOARD COMMITTEE (2017 - 2018)- NGO, SYMA

Unanimously Elected as a committee member for serving in NGO in multiple roles for a year

DATA SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING EVANGELIST - KAAR TECH OMEGA INITIATIVE

Got selected as <u>Data Science Evangelist</u> in Kaar Tech's Initiative for technological adoption into the company based on my initiatives taken within the company for Improving their exposure to Data Science and Engineering

### Courses and Certification

TAMING BIG DATA WITH MAP REDUCE AND HADOOP - LEARNING MAP REDUCE JOBS USING MRJOB - UDEMY

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER APPLICATION COURSE WITH CSC COMPUTER - C,C++